fas.ie 2016-11-26

# FÁS - Privacy Statement for FÁS

FÁS are committed to upholding all legislative requirements in regards to data protection and privacy. This statement will outline our privacy practices in association with this website. We are not responsible for privacy practices for other websites, which we provide, links to. All links to external websites are easily identifiable. Any technical terms used will be outlined in a glossary at the end of this statement. 

## Collection of your personal information

For some of the services, which FÁS offer, we may require information from you. The personal information we collect from you may include: name, gender, country of origin, date of birth, address, telephone and e-mail address & company name. 

Information may be collected on the IP addresses of the visitors webserver, the top-level domain used, previous website from which the visitor has visited us, clickstream data which shows the traffic of visitors around this website and the type of browsers used by the website visitor. This information is used to administer the site. 

## Use of your personal Information

The personal information collected will be used to provide the services of FÁS. 

By supplying this information you are implicitly agreeing to FÁS making your information available to a third party, this third party will also be required to register with FÁS. 

All information is validated by trained FÁS staff before it is stored on the website this helps ensure the integrity of all information. 

FÁS may disclose personal information if required to do so by law. 

Personal information collected on the site may be stored and processed in any country with which FÁS has an affiliation by using the site you consent to the transfer of your information. 

## Control of your personal information

Personal information may be shared with other registered users on the FÁS website. 

## Access to your personal information

All registered users will be provided with usernames and passwords, which can be used to access and make any changes to their information. 

## Security of your Personal Information

FÁS are committed to protecting the security of your personal information. FÁS follow best practice guidelines to help protect your information from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. Information is stored on computers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. 

## Protection of Children's Personal Information

FÁS do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. 

## Use of Cookies

The Jobbridge Internship section of the FAS website uses cookies. These cookies are encrypted and contain no personally identifiable information. All cookies have an expiration time after which they will be unusable. Website users should be aware that FAS will not delete any cookies stored locally on your machine however we will overwrite cookies each time a new session is started on our website. Deletion of cookies is entirely at your own discretion.

## Use of Google Analytics   

FAS use Google analytics to provide us with information on traffic on our website. Google analytics will collect information from you this information may include the following: 

  * Type of web browser used, software manufacture and version number.
  * Type of operating system
  * Network location and IP address
  * Time of visit
  * Pages visited
  * Time spent on each page of the website
  * Referring site statistics 
    * The website (URI) the user came through in order to arrive at this website (example: clicking on a hyperlink from Yahoo.com that took the user to this website) 
    * Search engine query used (example: typing in a phrase into a search engine like Google, and clicking on a link from that search engine) 

The above information will be collected by Google and may be stored on databases located outside of Ireland. The above information does not include any personally identifiable information. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.   

## Enforcement of this Privacy Statement

If you have any questions regarding the above statement please contact FÁS at the following address itadmin@FÁS.ie 

## Glossary:

### Web Browser

The piece of software you use to read web pages. Examples are Microsoft Internet Explorer, Netscape Navigator and Opera. 

### IP address

The identifying details for your computer (or your internet company's computer), expressed in "internet protocol" code (for example 192.168.72.34). Every computer connected to the web has a unique IP address, although this address may not be the same every time a connection is made. 

### Cookies

A cookie is a small data file that a website places on your hard drive for future use. Cookies can record your preferences when visiting a particular site and can help identify user trends for statistical analysis of our site. This can enable us, over time, to provide a better experience on our site by improving content, modifying navigation and generally making our site more user friendly. 

Without cookies, a web server has no memory of anything about a user's previous visits. It is important to note that accepting cookies used on our site does not give us access to any personal information. 

Most browsers automatically accept cookies by default, but you can usually refuse cookies or selectively accept cookies by adjusting the preferences in your browser.
